<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FantaEurovision</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on FantaEurovision</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 15:28:43 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/country/albania/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/albania/</guid><description>Anxhela Peristeri is an established Albanian singer, songwriter and model from the city of Korçë in the east of the country.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/australia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/australia/</guid><description>The voice of a new generation in Australia, Sydney-based artist and activist Montaigne (born Jess Cerro) has become an important name in the indie music scene. The past few years have seen her recognized for her work: her original songs voted on to Triple J Radio&amp;rsquo;s Hottest 100, an ARIA award for Best Breakthrough Artist and a nomination for Best Female Artist in 2016.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/austria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/austria/</guid><description>Inspired by his father’s performances fronting a local rock band, Vincent learned to play the piano, guitar, drums and bass by the age of 11.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/azerbaijan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/azerbaijan/</guid><description>Efendi has competed in popular musical programs, such as Yeni Ulduz, Böyük Səhnə (3rd place) and The Voice of Azerbaijan (3rd place). In 2017, she also took part and finished in 3rd place in the Silk Way Star, an international singing competition aired in Kazakhstan. In 2019, she successfully represented Azerbaijan at The Voice of Nur-Sultan, again in Kazakhstan.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/belgium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/belgium/</guid><description>For the past 25 years, Belgian band Hooverphonic has blurred the lines between symphonic soundscapes and highly infectious pop tunes. Never one to place all of his eggs in one basket, frontman Alex Callier has always strived to deliver quality songs, sung by the best singers in the business.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/bulgaria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/bulgaria/</guid><description>VICTORIA&amp;rsquo;s distinctive voice and style position her as one of the most promising new artists in Bulgaria. Her Eurovision 2021 entry &amp;lsquo;Growing Up is Getting Old&amp;rsquo; tells a tale of a journey to self-improvement by revisiting your roots and the places you feel safe.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/croatia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/croatia/</guid><description>Albina will represent Croatia at the first Semi-Final of the Eurovision Song Contest 2021 in Rotterdam with the song &amp;lsquo;Tick-Tock&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/cyprus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/cyprus/</guid><description>Cypriot broadcaster CyBC has announced that Elena Tsagrinou will represent the island nation at the Eurovision Song Contest 2021 in Rotterdam. The singer, who is signed to PANIK Records will perform the song “El Diablo”.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/czech-republic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/czech-republic/</guid><description>Benny Cristo, born Ben Cristovao, was born in the Czech city of Plzeň. He is a singer, lyric writer, sportsman and actor. Ben&amp;rsquo;s mother is from the Czech Republic and his father from the Southern Africa country of Angola.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/denmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/denmark/</guid><description>“Teenage idols your parents can understand!” - that’s how duo Fyr &amp;amp; Flamme describe themselves.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/estonia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/estonia/</guid><description>Born in the Estonian town of Võru, multi-talented Uku Suviste is a singer, pianist, composer and music producer. The entertainment industry flows through his veins as his father is a TV producer,and his mother a classically trained singer</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/finland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/finland/</guid><description>Blind Channel features Joel Hokka (vocals and guitar), Niko Vilhelm (vocals), Joonas Porko (guitar), Olli Matela (bass), Tommi Lalli (drums) and recent addition Aleksi Kaunisvesi (keyboards), giving the band the perfect number of members for the Eurovision Song Contest stage.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/france/</guid><description>Barbara Pravi will represent France at the Eurovision Song Contest 2021 in Rotterdam with the song &amp;lsquo;Voilà&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/georgia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/georgia/</guid><description>Tornike Kipiani was born 11 December 1987 in Tbilisi, Georgia. He is a musician, father of 3 children and a professional architect. When he founded his own band at age 19, he didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider becoming a vocalist. While Tornike and his bandmates looked for an additional member to fill that vacant spot, he stepped in temporarily, and the rest is history.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/germany/</guid><description>Where would Elton John be without his piano, or Lizzo if you took away her iconic flute solos? We don’t want to know, and the same applies to Jendrik and his ukulele.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/greece/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/greece/</guid><description>Stefania Liberakakis, known simply as Stefania, is a Greek-Dutch singer, actress and YouTuber. Stefania was born and raised in the Netherlands and, at a very young age, realized her love for music.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/iceland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/iceland/</guid><description>Daði Freyr, together with Icelandic broadcaster RÚV, has confirmed that he’ll be returning with his group Gagnamagnið to the Eurovision Song Contest in 2021.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/ireland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/ireland/</guid><description>Lesley Roy will represent Ireland at the Eurovision Song Contest in 2021 with a brand new song. Earlier she selected by RTÉ for Eurovision 2020 and now she gets a new chance to shine on the Eurovision stage.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/israel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/israel/</guid><description>Eden Alene’s roots stretch from her birthplace, Jerusalem, to her mother’s home country, Ethiopia.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/italy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/italy/</guid><description>Måneskin is a critically acclaimed band featuring vocalist Damiano, bassist Victoria, guitarist Thomas and Ethan on drums.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/latvia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/latvia/</guid><description>Samanta Tīna has competed in the Latvian selection for the Eurovision Song Contest no less than 6 times, finishing second twice – in 2012 and more notably in 2013 with the fan-beloved song, I Need a Hero. Not one to give up, Samanta has also twice attempted to represent her second home, Lithuania, in 2015 and 2017.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/lithuania/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/lithuania/</guid><description>The Roop is a group from Lithuania that consists of members Vaidotas Valiukevičius, Robertas Baranauskas, and Mantas Banišauskas. Their musical style can be described as a mix of rock, pop-rock, soft-rock, dance-rock, indie and pop.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/malta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/malta/</guid><description>Destiny lives on the island of Malta. From a tender age, she participated in singing competitions, where she succeeded triumphantly and was frequently referred to as a child prodigy.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/moldova/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/moldova/</guid><description>Natalia Gordienko was born on 11 December 1987 in Moldova&amp;rsquo;s capital Chisinau. She has been performing on the big stage since the age of 15.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/north-macedonia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/north-macedonia/</guid><description>From a child pop star to a member and soloist of the Chicago Children’s Choir to over 50 Opera roles and recitals at eminent music Festival across the world and collaborations with some of the world’s most prolific artists, Vasil’s motto in life is simple – wherever words fail – Vasil sings.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/norway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/norway/</guid><description>Andreas Haukeland, better known as TIX, hails from Bærum (just outside of Oslo) and is one of Norway&amp;rsquo;s most popular artists. TIX chose to perform the English version of his track Ut Av Mørket (Fallen Angel) at the Melodi Grand Prix final, a bold move that paid off as he’ll now perform at Eurovision Song Contest in Rotterdam this May.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/poland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/poland/</guid><description>Eurovision fans might recognise Rafał Brzozowski as a co-presenter of the 2020 Junior Eurovision Song Contest in Warsaw, Poland. His other TV work includes the popular music show The Name of the Tune and his time as co-host of the Polish version of Wheel of Fortune.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/portugal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/portugal/</guid><description>Portuguese band The Black Mamba won Festival da Canção 2021 and will represent Portugal at the Eurovision Song Contest in Rotterdam.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/romania/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/romania/</guid><description>Team Romania describe ROXEN as ‘a labyrinth of an artist, with a dreamy sound and mesmerising voice that creates an entirely new universe with every release’ - and it’s hard to disagree given the breadth of material the Cluj-Napoca chanteuse has released in recent times.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/russia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/russia/</guid><description>Some acts are described as ‘triple threats’, but Russia’s Manizha excels at so many different vocations, it’s impossible to describe the limit to her talents.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/san-marino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/san-marino/</guid><description>Born in Bologna to Eritrean parents, Senhit is a performer who combines her African roots with Italian style and a European electro-pop attitude.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/serbia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/serbia/</guid><description>Hurricane is back! Sanja Vučić, Ivana Nikolić and Ksenija Knežević will represent the country in Rotterdam with a brand new song.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/slovenia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/slovenia/</guid><description>Ana Soklič began her music career at an early age; studying with Alenka Dernač-Bunta, the acclaimed Slovenian musician Darja Švajger (two-time Slovenian representative at the Eurovision Song Contest) and singing coach Nataša Nahtigal.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/spain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/spain/</guid><description>Blas Cantó, born 26 October 1991, is one of the most influential musicians in the Hispanic pop music scene. He is a versatile artist, a perfectionist and a performer who thrives in front of a live audience. Blas’ hit solo album, Complicated, released in 2018, is described as an intimate album that shows the personality of the young artist, mixing different genres of music to bring his signature sound to life.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/sweden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/sweden/</guid><description>Tousin Michael Chiza, better known as Tusse, is a Swedish singer with Congolese roots who booked his ticket to Eurovision when he won &amp;lsquo;Melodifestivalen&amp;rsquo; by a landslide.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/switzerland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/switzerland/</guid><description>Gjon Muharremaj, from Broc in the Canton of Fribourg, has dedicated his heart and soul to music since he was a child. Moving his grandfather to tears with his rendition of Elvis Presley&amp;rsquo;s Can&amp;rsquo;t Help Falling in Love as a 9-year-old was a formative experience and the inspiration for his stage name: Gjon&amp;rsquo;s Tears. &amp;ldquo;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s joy, sadness or melancholy – I want to touch people with my music in every way.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/the-netherlands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/the-netherlands/</guid><description>Jeangu’s musical journey began when he received a guitar from his parents for his 13th birthday. Together with his twin brother Xillan, he formed a musical duo. However, his artistic ambitions proved bigger than the scene in his native Suriname and so he moved to the Netherlands at the age of 20.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/ukraine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/ukraine/</guid><description>Go_A creates modern reinterpretation of Ukrainian folklore packaged in electronic sound. The name of the group consists of &amp;lsquo;Go&amp;rsquo;, as &amp;lsquo;movement&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo;, as in the ancient Greek letter &amp;lsquo;alpha&amp;rsquo; which refers to going back to one&amp;rsquo;s cultural roots.</description></item><item><title/><link>/country/united-kingdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/country/united-kingdom/</guid><description>Award-winning singer-songwriter James Newman will represent the United Kingdom at the 65th Eurovision Song Contest in Rotterdam.</description></item></channel></rss>